#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/charmainebarreto-mpa-bsn-rn-ab46638a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

PALS

**BCLS** 

ACLS

Honors-Awards
NACLI Leadership Award
Academic Excellence

# Charmaine Barreto, MPA, BSN, RN

Clinical Nurse Manager at New York-Presbyterian Hospital Greater New York City Area

## Summary

Passionate, energetic and goal oriented with a strong commitment to helping people and delivering results. Offers a solid foundation in analytical tools and methodologies, pharmaceuticals and current healthcare advancements. With 10+ years experience in Perioperative Service and progressive management experience.

## Experience

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital

6 years 6 months

Clinical Nurse Manager August 2019 - Present (1 year)

Bronxville, New York

Post-Anesthesia Care Unit (PACU)

Clinical Nurse Manager
March 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 6 months)
Bronxville, New York

Operating Room

Clinical Nurse Manager (Weill Cornell)
September 2015 - February 2018 (2 years 6 months)
Manhattan, NY

Oversees Surgical Services: Gynecology (benign, oncology, REI, & robotics), Ophthalmology, General Surgery, Plastic Surgery, Bone Marrow, Robotic urology (adult & pediatrics)

Registered Nurse (Weill Cornell)
February 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 8 months)
manhattan, new york

Surgical Services (circulate/scrub): GYN, General, Plastic, Bone Marrow and Pulmonary.

Charge Nurse and initiated F10 Unit Practice Council (Chair)

Page 1 of 2

St. Barnabas Hospital (Level 1 Trauma)
Registered Nurse
August 2010 - February 2014 (3 years 7 months)
bronx, new york

Operating Room

Urology, Neurology, General, Plastic, Orthopedic, Trauma (Gen & Ortho Surg), Maxillo-Facial, Vascular Services

## Education

Case Western Reserve University DNP, Nursing Practice · (2019 - 2022)

NYU Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Master's Degree, Masters in Public Administration for Nurse Leaders · (2016 - 2018)

State University of New York Downstate Medical Center College of Medicine

Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2012 - 2013)